CORNELIA ONEA





Availability

Romania based with 1 week notice

 $\overline{\Delta}$

Phone: +40760386430

Email: cornelia.onea@gmail.com

Skype: cornelia_onea



SUMMARY

Guest-oriented, driven hospitality professional with over six years' experience in the cruise ship industry. Cornelia is a highly competent, capable and dedicated team player with a can-do positive attitude. Excellent management skills, including training, developing, coaching, and supervising front office/desk team members to achieve superior customer service and guest experiences and drive adherence to the cruise line policies and procedures. She has strong abilities in anticipating guest needs, follow-up on every detail and handling sensitive issues. Able to communicate effectively with all organization's levels, build relationships and trust and enlist the participation of team members. Demonstrated results in driving organisational growth and dynamic change, with proven successes in the areas of:

- Customer Service
- Front Desk Operation
- Meeting & Event Planning
- Budget management

- Group activities
- Program schedules
- · Coaching and training
- · Leadership & Management

EXPERIENCE

Feb 2018 – October 2019 FRONT DESK MANAGER Royal Caribbean International (Cruise Ship)

- Supervised a staff of 10 front desk officers and leading them to delivery extraordinary customer service;
- Assigned duties and shifts to the staff and observed performances to ensure adherence to company policies and established operating procedures;
- Trained team members how to respond to guest concerns in a considerate and professional manner;
- Responds quickly to all guest requests in a caring friendly and professional manner, consistently guest log follow up to ensure guest satisfaction that meets and exceed our services standards;
- Resolves guest complaints to the satisfaction of the customer by being guest centric, friendly and caring. Communicates to management any problems, complaints or unhappy guests;
- Participating in boarding process and documentation review, balancing operational needed between Financial and Guest Services;
- Executed shoreside reports as needed and meeting forecasted budget expectations.

January 2016 – November 2017 GROUPS EVENT COORDINATOR Royal Caribbean International (Cruise Ship)

- Planed, scheduled and managed designated programs: Full Ship Charters (up to 4500 guests), Corporate Groups (up to 1000 guests), VIP Groups, Meetings, Seminars, Weddings, Birthday Parties, Quinceaneras Party, Grand Openings, Captain Reception, Public Performance, Concerts, Ship Tours & Luncheon, media events etc.
- Worked with ship department heads to plan function details such as space requirement, audio-visual equipment,
 F&B services, decorations, entertainment, private excursions, etc
- Informed all departments of special functions by compiling a schedule of events listing any group requests and special needs prior to sailing and keeps updating during sailing if any changes are required.
- On embarkation day assisted with ship's tours and greeted group leaders offering any possible assistance to make their cruise experience special.
- · Resolved conflicts quickly and efficiently and provided alternative arrangements as needed.
- Assisting guest services when no groups on board (Concierge, Front Desk, Loyalty Ambassador, etc)

March 2013 – September 2015 CONCIERGE MSC CRUISES (Cruise Ship)

- Contact guests prior to their cruise vacation and assist with all the arrangements requested.
- Coordinated guests' special requests for onboard services (dining, specialty restaurants, shore excursions)
- Coordinated guests' requests for shore side services in ports (limousine services, car rentals, restaurant reservations, etc.);
- Handled guests' inquiries and complaints resolving them quickly, courteously, professionally and to the guests' total satisfaction.

October 2008 – December 2012 EVENT PLANNER SUPERVISOR GM DECO MANAGEMENT (Bucharest, Romania)

- Worked in a full-service event design, decoration & planning company. I created elegant and personalized events, unique floral arrangement and customized decor for special events: Weddings, Fashion Events, Corporate Events, Grand Openings, Birthday Parties, Kids parties.
- Planned, prepared and executed events.
- Worked in various event operations including the facility selection, contracting, pricing, transportation, accommodations, food and beverage selections, souvenir programs, and audio/visual service arrangements.
 Planned the event floor plan and its budget and produced the event materials, accessories, floral arrangement and decorations.
- Achieving business objectives through leads generated from seminars, special events and trade shows.
 Planned sales activities by identifying potential customers.
- Negotiated new contracts and renewals in order to meet sales targets.

EDUCATION

2018 - Present Master Degree of Business Administration University of Bucharest

2008 – 2011 Bachelor of Communication and Public Relations, University of Bucharest

2004 – 2008 Baccalaureate - High School level Diploma with emphasis in English, National College Roman-Voda

COURSES

STCW Basic Safety Training (HBST) Security Awareness Crowd Management (CMAT) Crisis Management B1B2 Visa valid
Seaman's Book
Hospitality Management Certificate
ALPS 1 – Accelerating Leadership Performance
Marketing, Events and Public Relations – Marketing Management Certificate

COMPUTER SKILLS

MS Office (Excel, Word, Outlook, PowerPoint), **Fidelio Cruises Management**, As400, Encore, AffairWhere Manager Cruise Ships, Lotus Notes, Adobe Photoshop, Corel Draw & many other programs for cruise ships.

LANGUAGES SKILLS

Romanian - native language English – advanced Italian, Spanish – basic level